<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<StructureDefinition xmlns="http://hl7.org/fhir" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://hl7.org/fhir ../../../__FHIRr4Tools/R4_fhir-all-xsd/structuredefinition.xsd">
	<id value="conformance-cen-ips"/>
	<url value="http://hl7.org/fhir/uv/ips/StructureDefinition/conformance-cen-ips"/>
	<name value="Conformance"/>
	<title value="Conformance attribute"/>
	<status value="draft"/>
	<description value="This attribute captures the level of requirement (mandatory, required, required if known, optional, conditional) for each specified element"/>
	<kind value="complex-type"/>
	<abstract value="true"/>
	<context>
		<type value="element"/>
		<expression value="ElementDefinition"/>
	</context>
	<type value="Extension"/>
	<baseDefinition value="http://hl7.org/fhir/StructureDefinition/Extension"/>
	<derivation value="constraint"/>
	<differential>
		<element id="Extension">
			<path value="Extension"/>
			<short value="Conformance"/>
			<definition value="The element shall assume one of the following values: &#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;M ; Mandatory (exceptions not allowed); A mandatory element shall always be present and - where applicable - shall be valorised with valid values. No exceptions or empty/null values are allowed in this case.&#xD;&#xA;If it refers to a composite element (e.g. a section, a list; a label concept) the presence of the included elements is determined by the conformance rules of these sub-elements.&#xD;&#xA;Recipient shall understand mandatory elements.&#xD;&#xA;If a ‘mandatory’ element is missing then the document is no longer a conformant IPS.&#xD;&#xA;A derived model (that includes also implementable specifications) shall maintain an equivalent conformance strength.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;R ; Required (exceptions allowed);  A required element shall always be present and - where applicable - should be valorised with valid values. Exceptions or empty/null values are allowed in this case.&#xD;&#xA;If it refers to a composite element (e.g. a section, a list; a label concept a complex data type) the presence of the included elements is determined by the conformance rules of these sub-elements.&#xD;&#xA;Recipient shall understand required elements.&#xD;&#xA;If a ‘required’ element is missing then the document is no longer a conformant IPS.&#xD;&#xA;A derived model (that includes also implementable specifications) shall maintain an equivalent conformance strength; or may further constrain it (e.g. from ‘R’ to ‘M’).&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;RK ; Required, if known; A “Required if known” element is one that should be provided.&#xD;&#xA;If there is information available, the element must be present and - where applicable - valorised with valid values.&#xD;&#xA;If there is no information available, the element may be omitted, may be left empty, or may be valorised with exceptional or null values depending on the implementation.&#xD;&#xA;If it refers to a composite element (e.g. a section, a list, a label concept, a complex data type) the presence of the included elements is determined by the conformance rules of these sub-elements.&#xD;&#xA;Recipient shall understand required elements.&#xD;&#xA;A derived model (that includes also implementable specifications) shall maintain an equivalent conformance strength; or may further constrain it (e.g. from ‘RK’ to ‘R’).&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;C; Conditional (has associated condition predicates); Depending on predicate conditions the element may assume different conformance strengths (e.g. O, R, RK) or not being present.&#xD;&#xA;A predicate can be simple (for example: «element A exists»; «attribute b = value1») or complex (for example: «element C exists» AND «the attribute x of element D = value2).&#xD;&#xA;A conditional element may be evaluated on a single condition (if predicate A then ‘Required’ else ‘Optional’) or on multiple conditions (e.g. if predicate A then ‘Required’; if predicate B then ‘Optional’; else ‘Not Present’).&#xD;&#xA;The resulting conformance strength (M, R, RK, O, ...) is determined by the conditions.&#xD;&#xA;If it refers to a composite element (e.g. a section, a list, a label concept, a complex data type) the presence of the included elements is determined by the combination of the predicate conditions of this element and the conformance rules of its sub-elements. For example:&#xD;&#xA;1. no exception is raised if a required sub-element is missing, when the parent is correctly omitted.&#xD;&#xA;2. an exception is raised if a required sub-element is missing, when the parent is present.&#xD;&#xA;Derived models or implementable specifications shall maintain an equivalent conformance strength; but it is allowed to modify the conformance strength if the predicate condition permits.&#xD;&#xA;Recipient shall understand conditional elements, when required. For example, a conditional element that could be optional or not present could be omitted by a derived model and ignored by a recipient. Or, a condition for which a conditional element become required doesn’t apply to a jurisdiction, in that case a jurisdictional specification could omit that element and recipient could ignore it.&#xD;&#xA;Depending on the conditions, exception is or is not raised if the data are missing.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;O; Optional ; This data element can be omitted from a derived model, including from implementations.&#xD;&#xA;Recipient may ignore optional elements.&#xD;&#xA;If it refers to a composite element (e.g. a section, a list, a label concept, a complex data type) the presence of the included elements is determined by the presence of this element and the conformance rules of its sub-elements. For example, no exception is raised if a required sub-element is missing, when the parent is omitted.&#xD;&#xA;The reason for specifying the optional data elements is to ensure that both sender and recipient use the appropriate semantic interpretation of these elements.&#xD;&#xA;No exception is raised if the data are missing."/>
			<alias value="Conformance"/>
		</element>
		<element id="Extension.value[x]">
			<path value="Extension.valueCode"/>
			<type>
				<code value="code"/>
			</type>
			<binding>
				<strength value="required"/>
				<valueSet value="http://hl7.org/fhir/uv/ips/ValueSet/conformance-cen-ips"></valueSet>
			</binding>
		</element>
	</differential>
</StructureDefinition>
